Preliminary Guide to the Peter H. Klopfer Papers, 1957-1971
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Peter H. Klopfer papers 1957-1971
University Archives, Duke University
Klopfer, Peter H.
1.5 Linear Feet 500 Items
Peter Klopfer is a Professor in the Department of Biology (previously known as Zoology).
This collection contains ledger books and information relating to grants and research proposals, ranging in date from 1957-1971.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Peter H. Klopfer Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977.
Biographical Note
Peter H. Klopfer was born August 9, 1930 in Berlin, Germany. He earned his B. A. degree (with honors) from the University of California at Los Angeles in 1952 and his Ph.D. from Yale University in 1957. In 1958, Professor Klopfer came to Duke as Assistant Professor in the Department of Zoology (now Dept. of Biology). In 1967, he was promoted to Professor. His area of research is animal behavior and behavioral ecology. His areas of interests are maternal attachment, aggression and species diversity. He was instrumental in starting the primate center at Duke. As of 2006, Klopfer is retired and is Professor Emeritus. However, he continues to do research, with his current project focusing on sleep and hibernation behavior in prosimian primates.
Collection Overview
Contains materials from the many grants Professor Klopfer received to fund his animal-behavior research. Included are ledger books, correspondence, research and grant paperwork, including applications. The collection ranges in date from 1957-1971.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Dept. of Biology
Duke University. Dept. of Zoology
Duke University. Faculty
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004
Duke University Archives
Biographical Reference Collection, 1972-2004
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Grant Material, circa 1969 (Box 1)
  - Grant Material, circa 1970
  - Grant Material, circa 1971
  - Grant Application
  - Grant Proposal Information, 1971
  - Stimulus Preferences and Imprinting, by Klopfer, 1967
  - National Science Foundation Grant Proposal, 1965-1966
  - Electronics Technician, 1962
  - Grant Award and Budget, 1967
  - Contract and Correspondence, 1967
  - Contracts and Correspondence, 1963-1964
  - Margarita Laboratory, 1966
  - Grant Proposal, 1966-1967
  - BSGG, Summer 1969
  - ONR, prior to 1967
  - ASB Bulletin, 1969 July
  - NASA contract, 1970-1971
  - NASA, circa 1968
  - New support sought, 1971
  - NASA, circa 1972
  - NC Heart Association
  - Grant Materials, 1968
  - NASA, 1971
  - Grant Information, circa 1971
  - Correspondence, 1967-1970
  - Ledgers, 1957-1970